# LYSANDRO CARIOCA BRAGA

Fortaleza, Ceara, Brazil Mobile: +55 85 997-569-542 Email: lysandroc@gmail.com

Software engineer with eight years of experience developing and scaling applications. Outstanding problem solver with an aptitude for troubleshooting and the ability to quickly master new skill technology.

# Programming Skills

- Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Golang, Java and SQL
- Technologies: React, Jest, NodeJS, GraphQL, AWS, Kubernetes, RabbitMQ, CouchDB and MongoDB

# EXPERIENCE

# • Stay22

Full Stack Software Developer

Nov. 2021 - Present

• Map: Developing the next map generation at Stay22. The API is written in Typescript, Nodejs and GraphQL, and the frontend uses Typescript, React, Mapbox and Styled Components. I also maintain internal common libraries shared between our internal products.

# • SysMap Solutions Software

Senior Software Engineer

Feb. 2021 - Oct. 2021

o Global Relationship Platform: A new product for Natura&Co to keep tracking of the beauty consultant relationship time in several countries. Implemented an event-driven design architecture to scale asynchronous relationship timing using AWS Lambda, SQS, NodeJS, and Scylla DB. Added new features ReactJS/Nodejs application. I've used Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Grafana and Kibana as a part of the devops process to scale and monitor the application.

#### • Instituto Atlântico

 $Senior\ Software\ Engineer$ 

Apr. 2020 - Feb. 2021

• 3D Printer Dashboard: Developed a system a as service for HP that shows all information about 3D printer usage. Implemented a thin REST layer written in Golang that reads information from the AWS Redshift; Created dashboards from Figma using React, React Hooks, Typescript; Contributed to the internal DevOps organization creating yaml template steps used across multiple teams.

# • OSF Digital

Senior Software Engineer

May 2019 - Apr. 2020

• **Private Pension**: A solution that offers a private pension fund to customers. Developed a web application from scratch using ReactJS, React Hooks, Context API, RTL, and Styled Components from Sketch UI; Code was covered by 85% of unit testing; Led a team of three developers to build an end to end testing project using the cypress framework.

### • Drugstore Pague Menos

Fortaleza, CE

Team Leader, Senior Software Engineer

Aug. 2013 - Apr. 2019

- Last Chance: A system that applies discounts for products near expiration date used by more than a thousand stores. I developed this application using ReactJS and .NET Core within five months and it increased the sales by around a million dollars monthly.
- Warehouse Order Picking System: A distributed system and data over CouchDB used to check and validate the picking process using the pick box method. Implemented a sample method algorithm to pick random boxes and reduce issues using Javascript; Optimized routines to clean up the local database on hundreds of workstations using NodeJS; Optimized the picking process from 2 hours to 5 minutes grouping them by transport routes.

#### EDUCATION

# • Postgraduate Diploma in Software Engineering

Universidade Estadual do Ceara

Fortaleza, CE

May. 2017 - Feb. 2019

• Associate of Science in Computer Science

Faculdade Tecnologica Lourenço Filho

Fortaleza, CE

Feb. 2012 - Dec. 2014